Hey guys, welcome back.
Let's talk about the next steps now,
okay, step number three.
So they took some time,
the business data analyst took some time
and uh, gave you a mapping sheet.
I'll show that to you shortly in fact,
and you will analyze the mapping sheet.
Okay? So here's the mapping sheet that they give to you
and it has multiple worksheets here.
The first one is about raw two curated, okay?
What they wanna see in the curated layer, okay?
You have source field section here.
This has all the fields in the
H-V-F-H-V table, okay?
So if you go to the glue catalog, log AWS glue,
and then go to databases here, go to our database
and look at our table.
So you will have all the different fields
right here, in fact, right?
We have actually 20
and uh, we have more fields here you go
to, yep, there you go.
27 fields.
It shows here because the last two are actually partition
columns, but the data is actually in 25 columns.
So going back to my mapping sheet, so you have
all the source fields from the source, right?
And their data types is mentioned here
and how they really wanna see in the curated layer,
the target field names.
And if you scroll down a bit, there are more fields
that they wanna see right?
From here, these are all N-A-N-A-N-A,
but here you have the new fields
that they wanna see in target fields.
Essentially, this is what I meant by business rules, okay?
Essentially they're asking us to create new fields, okay?
Based on this, these fields, right?
For example, pick power,
pickup power is not in the source file,
but you do have pickup date time, right?
You do have pickup date time from the pickup date time,
which is a timestamp field.
Let me show you how it looks like.
If I go to back to Athena
and uh, click on this, uh, review table,
it's gonna fire query automatically.
And there you go. So you have pick up daytime.
So the how is also here, in fact.
So they wanna derive the how from this data.
That's a transformation, right?
That is what is transformation.
That is what we do as data engineers.
We transform the data and move data from
one location to another location.
So they want us
to create the pickup power from pickup daytime.
Likewise, they wanna create a date field
from pickup daytime, okay?
From the timestamp field. They wanna get the date itself.
They wanna divide
that one field into multiple trip date pickup power,
and also day off week, whether it's weekend or not.
So essentially you have
The logic mentioned here.
So they have given you the logic
based on which you'll create these new columns in the
curated layer from your code.
When you write, when, when you write the code to
read the data in the raw folder
and create the data in the curated folder, you will want
to create additional fields based on
these transformation logic mentioned here.
Okay? Like, let's take a look at these also, right?
So here, I mean you have some transformation mentioned
for the existing fields as well, okay?
For example, you see here for the first three, uh,
they have, uh, not mentioned any transformation.
Direct pass through whatever is in source, just load
as is in curated.
When I say source, whatever is there in raw
load as is in curated.
Now, if you scroll down a bit here,
see here you have some business logic here, in fact,
for this flag, shared request flag, shared match flag, all
of these different flags.
If the data has y why y then you change
that to a Boolean value.
Okay? I hope you know what a bullion is.
I have discussed this in the SQL skill booster code.
So I mean, you have to be able to, uh, understand this.
I'm assuming you have gone through the
SQL skill booster course.
So if at all the value of these is,
let's say why, why, why, why in the raw data,
then change it to true else.
If it is not why, then they need to false.
So our job now is as data engineers to understand this
and ask the analyst team you have, if you have any questions
and get clarifications on,
and then use this mapping sheet,
this transformation logic mentioned here to build our code,
which we'll see later, in fact, okay,
I hope this much is clear so far.
So this, for the raw two curated mapping only,
and remember we talked about data quality
rules as well in the past, right?
So they have given us some data quality rules to check.
After we do the curation, we also want to
validate the data against some rules, okay?
For example, whether the pick up data time drop
of the time is, uh, null.
If it is null, reject the record
as mentioned here, reject the record.
Let me just, uh, zoom out a bit.
So the null checks are being done here.
And then the rain check trip miles, right?
Trip miles must be between zero and 500.
This for New York City only.
New York City is pretty small, in fact, okay?
It's just, it's the Manan is an island, in fact.
So obviously the New York City
trips cannot really be more than 500 miles.
That's a business rain check, okay?
The base fare must be positive
and under $10,000, I mean obviously if at all
the base fare goes beyond that, it could be,
uh, invalid record.
So they're saying reject the record as such.
And you have some logical checks as well.
I mean, obviously the drop off must be after pickup, right?
I mean, it's obvious
that the drop off will happen only after pickup.
See if at all the data doesn't look like that, it means
that the record is invalid.
So reject the record, right?
There are some more here, in fact.
So take a look at them, you'll come to,
it's a pretty straightforward, in fact, okay?
So these data quality rules will have
to implement in our code also, and not just raw to curate.
They've also given us curated to aggregated mapping
as well, which is right here.
In fact, similar to, you know, what we just discussed.
You know, they are now letting us know
how they wanna see the data in the aggregated layer, daily
aggregations, they wanna see.
And here are the source fields.
Here, there are the metrics
based on what they wanna aggregate.
In a sense. The source field is trip files
and they wanna do some aggregations, right?
And I say aggregations again, the S QL thing comes
to picture here, okay?
Um, the total trip piles, trip miles, average trip miles,
minimum trip miles, max trip miles.
So these are aggregations they wanna see, okay?
And the total fair amount, total revenue.
Likewise, we have a lot
of different metrics you wanna see, okay?
And they've also listed down how to get the exact pickup,
borrow pickup zone I
talked about in the previous video, right?
By joining to the zone table here, in fact, okay?
And they've given us a join logic called impact, okay?
How to join them based on
what everything is mentioned, in fact.
And in this column, they have also given us
the aggregation function.
How, how do you wanna aggregate them? Okay?
So everything is mentioned here, in fact.
So this is the kind of mapping sheet that is given to us,
and we go through this and we understand this,
and then we implement our code, this in our code, in fact.
So this is what we do, and
after we analyze the mapping sheet,
we decide on the technical requirements
that will lock in the next video.